Hi, John! are you riding in a car?
Hi, Faith! Yes, my friend is taking me to the airport.
Turn left at the intersection, then go straight.
So, John, what's our lesson for today?
Well, I think we should discuss cars.
Really? How so?
A car is a vehicle for getting people or goods across an area.
We can think of a sentence as a vehicle for getting information across to other people.
I see.
And we might use sentences for special purposes
- just as we might use a kind of car for a special purpose.
Can you think of an example?
The imperative sentence.
The imperative sentence generally consists of a predicate.
The subject is left out.
You recently heard an example of an imperative sentence:
Turn left at the intersection then go straight.
You might compare imperative sentences to race cars.
Race cars are designed for getting from one point to another point as fast as possible
Race car makers take out many elements to get the lowest possible weight.
For example, race cars do not have sound systems or seats for passengers.
In the same way, imperative statements are designed for getting meaning across as fast as possible.
Speakers take out important sentence elements to express information as quickly as possible
And that's Everyday Grammar TV
Don't forget to watch more of our videos at our website. learningenglish.voanews.com