Hi, John.
Hi, Faith!
Let's continue our lesson on grammar and cars.
A quick reminder for our viewers:
Just as there are different kinds of cars,
there are also different kinds of sentences.
Let's turn our attention to a kind of sentence you are likely to hear or use when driving:
exclamatory sentences.
Grammar books describe exclamatory sentences in two ways:
in terms of emotion and in terms of word order.
The first way we describe exclamatory sentences
is in terms of emotion.
When we are driving, that emotion is often - but not always - negative.
I can't believe he cut me off!
The second kind of exclamatory sentence involves a change of word order.
We often use "what" or "how" in these kinds of statements.
We also often leave out the verb.
For example, imagine you are stuck in heavy traffic.
A person speeds up and cuts in front of you.
You might say in a negative tone:
"What a piece of work!"
or something like this:
"what the --- !"
This kind of exclamatory sentence is not polite,
and we do not suggest using it.
But you might hear it or something like it in a film or in real life.
And That's Everyday Grammar TV.
Don't forget to watch more of our videos at our website. learningenglish.voanews.com