Hi, Dr. Jill!
What's on your mind today?
I recently went to a farmer's market.
I heard so many people discussing prices.
It's an important subject to explore.
You know, Dr. Jill, I love comparisons.
They really help make learning more enjoyable.
When I teach about price discussions,
I like to make a comparison to a movie.
Let's call our movie "Price Questions."
The star of our film is "how much."
"How much" often appears in questions about prices
just like a main actor appears in many of the scenes in a movie.
If we continue the comparison,
we could say that the verb "cost" is the most important supporting actor.
But sometimes it is left out
just like how a supporting actor might appear in fewer scenes in a film.
Finally, we have a few background actors.
You might not notice them as much.
These are words such as "do," "be," "that," "it," or "this."
Let's take an example.
How much does this cost?
The general order of appearance is this:
How much + helping verb + subject + main verb (cost)
There is much more to say about price discussions.
But we will have to cover those issues in a future lesson.
And that's Everyday Grammar TV.
Don't forget to watch more of our videos at our website. learningenglish.voanews.com