Hi, John!
Let's continue our lesson on price discussions.
Absolutely - it's such a fun and useful topic.
Here is a quick reminder.
In the previous lesson, we explored this question:
How much does this cost?
We compared "how much" to the star far of a movie.
"How much" often appears in questions about prices
just like the main star appears in most scenes in a movie.
We mentioned that other words in our example question are sometimes left out.
We compared these words to supporting actors or background actors
How much does this cost?
For example, we sometimes leave out the verb "cost."
And in some cases, we leave out the helping verb "do."
Instead, we use the verb "be."
I like to compare "be" to a kind of stunt double for "do."
For example, instead of asking "how much does this cost?,"
A person might ask "how much is this?"
or
"how much is it?."
Please note these three questions have almost the same meaning:
How much does this cost?
How much is this?
How much is it?
Let's end with a quiz.
Imagine you see an object for sale.
What are two ways to ask about the price?
Here are two possible answers"
How much does this cost?
How much is this?
And that's Everyday Grammar TV.