Welcome to English in a Minute!
A "sketch" is a simple drawing
meant to show the main parts of something.
But, what does it mean if something is sketchy?
So, are you doing anything fun over the long weekend?
Yes! I'm going on a midnight hike at Fort Danger Park
Is that a good idea?
Weird things happen at Fort Danger Park even in the daytime
It's not as sketchy as people think
I hike there at night all the time!
Of course you do.
Sketchy has a couple of meanings.
It can describe something that is not complete or clear
But it can also describe something dangerous or bad.
This usage of the word is very casual and informal
And that's English in a Minute!