Welcome to English in a minute
a third degree burn requires medical attention
but is this what Ana and Dan are talking about when they say the third degree.
Hey, I'm headed to the lunch meeting
you want to walk with me
No thanks. I 'm busy doing other things far away with other people.
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Who are you meeting?
Dan, stop with the third degree!
If you don't want so many questions, I need answers.
A third degree is a long and intense period of questioning
We usually call it the third degree.
It is what police officers do to get information
or even a confession from a suspect
and that's English in a minute.