Hello! I'm John Russell.
Let's continue our exploration of common words,
phrases and questions in American English.
In recent lessons, we talked about how to ask for directions.
But what do you say when someone asks you for directions?
Two words are especially important for giving directions:
left and right.
Today we will focus on the word "left."
We can start by breaking the word into its individual sounds.
We have one vowel sound and a few consonant sounds.
Let's start with the last sound first.
Watch my mouth carefully and repeat after me:
/t/
Now let's do the last two consonant sound slowly.
Pay careful attention to my lips.
/ft/
The vowel sound comes next.
Once again, pay careful attention to my mouth.
Repeat after me:
/e/
/eft/
We are almost done with the word.
We have one final consonant sound
the tricky "l" sound.
Watch closely, listen, and repeat after me.
/l/
/left/
That's all for today!
Keep up the good work!
Don't forget to watch more of our videos at our website. learningenglish.voanews.com